let quiz = {
    chapter: 'Nutrition, Health & Disease',
    topics: [
        'Vitamins',
        'Minerals',
        'HIV',
        'WHO',
        'Hydroponics',
        'Antibiotic',
        'Virus',
        'Bacteria',
    ],
    title: 'Nutrition, Health & Disease',
    colors: ['#096c86', '#096c8636', '#dbf6fb'],
    questions: [
        {
            question: 'The site of photosynthesis in plants is',
            options: [
                'mitochondria ',
                'chloroplasts',
                'leucoplasts ',
                'dictyosomes',
            ],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question: 'Autotrophic nutrition occurs in',
            options: [
                'fungi',
                'plants',
                'some protists and prokaryotes',
                'Both B and C',
            ],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'Select the correct statement.',
            options: [
                'Heterotrophs do not synthesise their own food.',
                'Heterotrophs utilise solar energy for photosynthesis.',
                'Heterotrophs synthesise their own food.',
                'Heterotrophs are capable of converting carbon dioxide and water into carbo-hydrates.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Select the statement which does not occur during the process of photosynthesis.',
            statement: [
                'Absorption of light energy by chlorophyll.',
                'Conversion of chemical energy to light energy and splitting of water molecules into hydrogen and oxygen.',
                'Oxidation of carbon dioxide to carbohydrates.',
            ],
            options: ['1 and 2', '1 and 3', '2 and 3 ', 'All of the above'],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question: 'Match The Column',
            table: {
                left: ['parasites', 'saprophytes', 'Autotrophs', 'Holozoic'],
                right: ['fungi', 'Humans', 'Leech', 'Algae.'],
            },
            options: [
                'A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4',
                'A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2',
                'A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4',
                'A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2',
            ],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question: 'Which of the following is a micronutrient element-',
            options: ['Mg ', 'K', 'Ca ', 'Zn'],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'Erythropoesis may be stimulated by the deficiency of',
            options: ['Iron ', 'Oxygen', 'Protein ', 'None of the above'],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Stomata : gaseous exchange from leaves : gaseous exchange from bark cells',
            options: ['cuticles ', 'pores', 'stomata ', 'lenticels'],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'Exchange of gases in leaf occurs through',
            options: [
                'tentacles ',
                'skin of the leaf',
                'stomata ',
                'root hair',
            ],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question: 'Which mineral is obtained from the atmosphere?',
            options: ['Potassium ', 'Iron', 'Magnesium ', 'Nitrogen'],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Photosynthesis is an important mode of autotrophic nutrition. The event which does not occur in photosynthesis is',
            options: [
                'Conversion of light energy to chemical energy',
                'Reduction of carbon dioxide to carbohydrate',
                'Oxidation of carbon to carbondioxide',
                'Absorption of light energy by chlorophyll',
            ],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question: 'Hydroponics refers to the plant development',
            options: [
                'without soil.',
                'in saline soil.',
                'in water without soil.',
                'without soil with alkaline pH.',
            ],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question:
                'The major role of minor elements inside living organisms is to act as',
            options: [
                'binder of cell structure.',
                'co-factors of enzymes.',
                'building blocks of important amino acids.',
                'constituent of hormones.',
            ],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following is not caused by deficiency of mineral nutrition?',
            options: [
                'Necrosis',
                'Chlorosis',
                'Etiolation',
                'Shortening of internodes',
            ],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question: 'Boron in green plants assists in',
            options: [
                'sugar transport',
                'activation of enzymes',
                'acting as enzyme cofactor',
                'photosynthesis',
            ],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following elements are constituents of protein?',
            options: [
                'Nitrogen and phosphorus',
                'Nitrogen and chlorine',
                'Phosphorus and boron',
                'Chlorine and potassium',
            ],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question: 'Nitrogen fixation is a process of',
            options: [
                'converting nitrogen in the air to form a usable form by plants.',
                'recycling nitrogen from organic matter in the soil.',
                'absorbing nitrogen from the soil.',
                'conversion of NO<sub>3</sub> to N<sub>2</sub> .',
            ],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following statements is not correct about macro- nutrients?',
            options: [
                'They are present in plant tissues in excess of 100 m mole per kg of dry matter.',
                'They include C, H, O, N, P, S, K, Ca, Mg.',
                'Some elements attained from CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>O while the others are absorbed from the soil.',
                'C, H & O are mainly obtained from CO<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>O.',
            ],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question: 'Match The Column',
            table: {
                left: ['K', 'Mo', 'P', 'Mn'],
                right: [
                    'Stomatal opening',
                    'Constituent of cell membrane',
                    'Photolysis of water',
                    'Free ion',
                    'Component of nitrogenase and nitrate reductase',
                ],
            },
            options: [
                'A-1,4, B-5, C-2, D-3',
                'A-1,5, B-4, C-3, D-2',
                'A-1,5, B-4, C-2, D-3',
                'A-4, B-1, C-3, D-2,5',
            ],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question: 'Match The Column',
            table: {
                left: ['Zinc', 'Sulphur', 'Magnesium', 'Molybdenum'],
                right: ['Chlorophyll', 'IAA', 'Nitrate reductase', 'Cysteine'],
            },
            options: [
                'A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4',
                'A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2',
                'A-3, B-1, C-2, D-4',
                'A-2, B-4, C-1, D-3',
            ],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'Passive immunity was discovered by',
            options: [
                'Robert Koch',
                'L. Pasteur',
                'Edward Jenner',
                'Eemil Von Behring',
            ],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'The term “antibiotic” was coined by',
            options: [
                'Alexander fleming',
                'Edward Jenner',
                'Louis Pasteur',
                'Selman waksman',
            ],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'The malignant tertian malaria is caused by',
            options: [
                'Plasmodium vivax',
                'Plasmodium falciparum',
                'Plasmodium ovale',
                'Plasmodium malaria',
            ],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question: '‘Black death’ is related with',
            options: ['plague', 'cancer', 'tuberculosis', 'measles'],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question: 'Match The Column',
            table: {
                left: ['Streptomycin', 'Chloroquine', 'Penicillin', 'Insulin'],
                right: [
                    'Viral Disease',
                    'Diabetes Mellitus',
                    'Disease caused by Bacteria',
                    'Malaria',
                ],
            },
            options: [
                'A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2',
                'A-3, B-4, C-2, D-1',
                'A-3, B-2, C-1, D-4',
                'A-1, B-2, C-3, D-4',
            ],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question: 'Match The Column',
            table: {
                left: ['Small pox', 'Cholera', 'Malaria', 'Anaemia'],
                right: [
                    'Bacteria',
                    'Virus',
                    'Deficiency of minerals',
                    'Female mosquito',
                ],
            },
            options: [
                'A-4, B-2, C-3, D-1',
                'A-2, B-1, C-4, D-3',
                'A-4, B-3, C-2, D-1',
                'A-3, B-4, C-1, D-2',
            ],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question: 'DPT vaccine stands for',
            options: [
                'diphtheria, polio & tuberculosis',
                'diphtheria, pertussis & tuberculosis',
                'diphtheria, polio & tetanus',
                'diphtheria, pertussis and tetanus',
            ],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'Which Vector Spread the yellow fever disease?',
            options: [
                'Musca sp ',
                'Anopheles sp',
                'Culex sp ',
                'Aedes aegypti',
            ],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'Which of the following is an air-borne disease?',
            options: ['Tuberculosis ', 'Cholera', 'Jaundice ', 'Brain fever'],
            answer: 1,
        },
        {
            question: 'Which of the following is a communicable disease?',
            options: ['Phenylketoneuria ', 'Cancer', 'Rabies ', 'Alkaptonuria'],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following disease is confirmed by ‘widal test’?',
            options: ['Tuberculosis ', 'Typhoid', 'Plague ', 'Tetanus'],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question: '“Athlete’s Foot” is a disease caused by [IAS Prelim]',
            options: ['Bacteria ', 'Fungus', 'Protozoan ', 'Nematode'],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question:
                'According to the World Health Organisation (WHO), the disease which causes the death of the largest number of people today is [IAS Prelim]',
            options: ['AIDS ', 'Tuberculosis', 'Malaria ', 'Ebola'],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Which of the following are associated with Diabetes mellitus, a common disease in adults ? [IAS Prelim]',
            statement: [
                'Higher sugar level in blood',
                'Lower sugar level in blood',
                'Lower insulin level in blood',
                'Higher insulin level in blood',
            ],
            options: ['2 and 4 ', '1 and 2', '2 and 3 ', '1 and 3'],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Consider the following statements. AIDS -is transmitted [IAS Prelim]',
            statement: [
                'By sexual intercourse',
                'By blood transfusion',
                'By mosquitoes and other blood sucking insects',
                'Across the placenta',
            ],
            options: [
                '1, 2 and 3 are correct',
                '1, 2 and 4 are correct',
                '1, 3 and 4 are correct',
                '1 and 3 are correct',
            ],
            answer: 2,
        },
        {
            question:
                'People drinking water from a shallow hand pump, are likely to suffer from all of the following diseases except [IAS Prelim]',
            options: ['Cholera ', 'Typhoid', 'Jaundice ', 'Fluorosis'],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question:
                'The major chemical compound found in kidney stones is : [IAS Prelim]',
            options: [
                'urea',
                'calcium carbonate',
                'calcium oxalate',
                'calcium sulphate',
            ],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question: 'Antigen is a substance which [IAS Prelim]',
            options: [
                'lowers body temperatures',
                'destroys harmful bacteria',
                'triggers the immune system',
                'is used as an antidote to poison',
            ],
            answer: 3,
        },
        {
            question:
                'Haemophilia is a genetic disorder which leads to [IAS Prelim]',
            options: [
                'decrease in haemoglobin level',
                'rheumatic heart disease',
                'decrease in WBC',
                'non-clotting of blood',
            ],
            answer: 4,
        },
        {
            question: 'Match The Column [IAS Prelim]',
            table: {
                left: ['Atropine', 'Ether', 'Nitroglycerine', 'Pyrethrin'],
                right: [
                    'Local anaesthesia',
                    'Heart trouble',
                    'Dilation of pupil',
                    'Mosquito control',
                ],
            },
            options: [
                'A-1, B-3, C-2, D-4',
                'A-1, B-3, C-4, D-2',
                'A-3, B-1, C-4, D-2',
                'A-3, B-1, C-2, D-4',
            ],
            answer: 2,
        },
    ],
};
